Jai Hind friends, you are very welcome
again to a new educational video, friends,
in today's video we will learn single, if
you want to do something or print it, then we will do it from here
and that too will be that
particular sheet is a small format, so first of all
we will learn that
if you have a sheet open and are making a report, then
you have to send only this report, you do not care about whatever is written around this report that you are seeing, you have to
send only the area that is told to you, so what
you have to do is
select the area that you want to send in a precise manner, we have done a little bit
more, after selecting it
you have to set its page, to
set the page you will see a page layout
tab at the top, go to that page layout tab,
go to print area and from
here click on set print area,
if you click on set print area, then
this area has been set for your printable,
right if you
click the cursor outside then you  You will see
a lining on it like this, now
what you have to do is go to the file,
after going to the file, go to the print option, now
as you go to the print option, the same
thing will be visible which you have set for printable, so
this is what I am seeing,
now I have to save it, so to save it, go to the
printer option which will
come here, here you will
see an option of PDF or you
can also save it in XPS document writer, so from here we select it,
now after selecting, page
size etc. everything is given, what will we do from here, we will
click on the print option,
now as friends, when we click on the print option,
now friends, you will see a small dialog
box here of save, in which the
file is being saved with the name of XPS, so
we remove it and rename the file with Excel
, CL and from here we
save it in XPS document,
so this data gets saved as mine, now if we
see, this data of mine has been saved here,
right only mine  The report has been saved,
now I have to mail it, so
what will we do to mail it,
friends, if the interface is not visible like this, then by going
here, you can type this
dot-na-dot,
like
aati ku 6@gmail.com, after typing here, we
give the subject, if it is e SL Ekal
's bill or file or
anything, then we type it here, this will be
your heading, it will be created with this heading,
what have you to do after that, you have to go to the
attribute file,
after going to the attribute file, you have to select the file from here
which you have saved, so here is the
file of Ekal, we open it from here, once we
open it, it will take some time
and this file of yours will be exported here,
it will be uploaded,
after uploading, if you click on the send button from here, then
what will happen to your file, it will be sent,
now what you have to do is
go to the send option from here and check once that the
file which I have sent  If it has been sent then of
course it will show you this file here on send, from
here you can click and see
that this file of yours has already been
sent, so this file of yours has been
sent, so friends, in this way you
can easily send any Excel data to someone else's document by selecting any particular area and saving that data, so friends,
if you like the video then give it a like
and if you are new to my channel then
subscribe to the channel for similar content,
then we will meet in the next video, till then
Jai Hind, have a nice day